

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

■ me@joshoberhaus.com | ↑ www.joshoberhaus.com | ☐ joshOberhaus | ☐ joshoberhaus

With eight years specializing in Driver Assistance, I bring expertise in Radar-based tracking and fusion, alongside a diverse skill set developed from a total of 14 years in the automotive industry. Committed to ongoing learning while also empowering colleagues; I have revamped visualization tools, introduced two generations of tracking KPI tools, and conducted various training sessions on perception and fusion - all to make working on tracking more accessible and enjoyable. I am strong team player, as demonstrated by leading critical customer meetings and stepping into the role of Product Owner as needed. I am eager to contribute to a new team!

Experience

Robert Bosch LLC Hybrid | Plymouth, MI

TECHNICAL EXPERT - PERCEPTION | TRACKING SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PERCEPTION | TRACKING

Jan. 2024 - Present Sep. 2018 - Jan. 2024

- Served as a technical lead for a global platform Perception / Tracking software team.
- Secured a strategic acquistion through realizing tracking gains brought by architectural changes for a 5 radar 1 video configuration.
- Optimized radar-based perception for a new generation of radar sensor.
- Developed several new features for MATLAB-based tracking visualization tooling, including projection of the components of the Kalman filter, and automation abilities.
- Coordinated with cross-functional software teams and management to determine long term planning of software content and integration strategies.
- · Supported and led critical customer demos and meetings, even outside of my main area of expertise.
- · Acted as Product Owner for an Agile System-of-Systems team.
- Developed Python-based KPI Tool for single target tracking analysis, integrated and automated its execution as a Jenkins pipeline.
- Increased performance of corner radar-based tracking (C++) by identifying and addressing assumptions made towards front-facing radars.
- · Reworked object type classification feature calculations to be more agnostic of sensor-mounting, reducing missed-target scenarios.

Bosch Engineering North America

Farmington Hills, MI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PREDICTIVE SAFETY SYSTEMS

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2018

- · Served as the Predictive Safety System (AEB, FCW, System Conditioning) Component Responsible for a strategic customer.
- Developed Python-based data mining tools to open new opportunities in evaluating data sets from endurance runs.
- · Introduced automated tooling to enable customer-friendly overviews for endurance run points of interest.
- · Led labelling sessions with the customer, explaining and addressing concerns with any activations.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Apr. 2012 - Apr. 2016

- Developed unique solution for criticality classification for marine radar collision warning applications, modified tracking and localization logic to be less dependent on traffic scenes.
- Designed and implemented Python-based code generation tool chain to allow a Bosch-created library to be integrated into a third-party controller.
- Created an ABS simulation software (C-based) and testing client (in CANAPE/CAPL) for OEM brake component testing, greatly reducing the OEM endurance run effort.
- · Served as diagnostic Component Responsible and integrator in Electronic Power Steering (EPS) and EBCM projects.
- Integrated ASIL-D control functions in EPS unit, to facilitate level three functions, the first for that product generation.
- · Led a global diagnostic communication software development team, coordinating tasks and workloads.

Skills

Programming C++, Python, MATLAB, C, Julia

Middleware Automotive Operating System (AOS), ROS

Education & Certificates

Kettering University Flint, MI

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SUMMA CUM LAUDE

Coursera

Deep Learning Specialization 2023